Guide to the Alfred Bosworth papers, 1899-1956.
Bosworth, Alfred papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alfred Bosworth papers, 1899-1956.
22-2-3998
Bosworth, Alfred Wilson
2.4 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, newspapers, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, publications,photographs, and newspaper clippings concerning his work at the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, the Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children, the Kellogg and Postum Cereal Companies, and his development of Similac Infant Formula.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Alfred Bosworth was an assistant and associate chemist at the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station at Geneva between 1905-1916. While there he studied the chemical and biological processes involved in the ripening of cheese and conducted studies on the composition of several types of milk, including human milk. During this time Bosworth developed an interest in infant feeding which paved the way for the discovery of Similac Infant Formula.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, publications, newspaper clippings concerning his work at the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, the Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children, the Kellogg and Postum Cereal Companies, and his development of Similac Infant Formula.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bosworth, Alfred Wilson.; Bosworth, Alfred Wilson.; Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Kellogg Company; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.; Postum Cereal Co.; Similac
Subjects:
Children -- Hospitals; Breastfeeding.; Infants -- Nutrition; Malnutrition; Infant formula industry -- United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Material
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Reports
Series IV. Publications
Series V. Various other Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Material
  - Biographical Information, 1900-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information-including bibliography, 1900-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bosworth's Reprints, 1915-1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Bosworth (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Harvard, 1907-1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Application for Employment in Biochemistry-University of Manitoba, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Civil Service Application and Rating, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Bosworth seeking employment, 19121-1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence concerning Ohio State position, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Auerbacher, L.J., 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Blanchard, Marguerite, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bowditch and Crown, Cork and Seal Company, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Elsie, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dennett, Roger H., 1919-1926 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dorr, Dudley, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fischer, Martin, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - McCann, Marion, 1920-1923 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - VanSlyke, D.D., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Wheeler, H.J., 1899-1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Wilder, H.K., 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Snell, F.D., 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Concerning Copyright, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence to Bosworth, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence from People Requesting Bosworth's Infant Formula, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Concerning Boston Floating Hospital, 1913-1937 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Concerning Boston Floating Hospital and their Board of Trustees, 1915-1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Concerning Boston Floating Hospital, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 26A)
  - Buffalo Foundry and Machine Company, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dodge and Sons - Attorneys, 1917-1923 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Doughitt Engineering, includes plans, 1925-1940 (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
  - Dry Milk Company, 1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Elmer and Amend Company, 1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Kellogg Company, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mead Johnson and Company, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mellin's Food Company; Massachusetts Commission on Mental Diseases (includes proposals), 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Merrell-Soule Company, Syracuse, New York, 1914-1922 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - National Canners Association, 1917-1924 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, Geneva, New York, 1905-1913 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Scientific Materials Company, 1919-1931 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Postum Company and R.G. Coburn, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Washington Agricultural Experiment Station; George Washington Coffee Refining Company, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence with various companies about buying products and labels for infant formula, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Nucoa Butter Company and Abbott Labs, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence concerning purchase orders, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Series III. Reports
  - Commissions, 1904-1918 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Commissions-United States Department of Agriculture, 1904-1921 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Boston Floating Hospital-Annual Reports (1918, 1921); Reprints (1921-1934); By-laws, 1921-1934 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Bosworth's Infant Food; Similac-includes articles, 1921-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kellogg Labs-about Kellogg flavor, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Bicarbonate Milk Powder, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Butter Fat, 1924-1935 (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
  - Butter Oil, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Infant Food, 1924-1926 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fat of Women's Milk-Studies, 1934-1934 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Milk Powder-correspondence, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Milk Powder-Sales Portfolio, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Milk Powder-Plant Data (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Milk Powder-Reports, Contracts, Correspondence, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Milk Powder-Memos, Data, Correspondence, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Milk Powder-American Dry Milk Institute- Annual Business Meeting, April 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Milk Powder-American Dry Milk Institute-First Annual Meeting, April 1926 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Milk Powder-Paper given at 4th Annual American Dry Milk Institute, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Milk Powder-Report by Fritz Krull and other Publications (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Lab Reports of People Given Reconstructed Milk, 1918-1923 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sweetened Condensed Milk (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Methods of Anaysis, 1920-1923 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sketch of the Life and Work of Alfred Bosworth-Vol. V, 1879-1921 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Reconstructed Milk and the Chemical Investigations Involved with its Development, Lecture-Vol. VI, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - Bosworth's Reconstructed Milk, Franklin Infant Food, Similac-Vol. VII, 1924-1958 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Sketch of the Life and Work of Alfred Bosworth-Vol. VIII, 1919-1958 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Agreements-Vol. IX, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Chemistry of Milk in its Relation to Infant Feeding-Vol. X (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Series IV. Publications
  - Articles, 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper clippings, Correspondence, Reports, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Outline for a Process for Making Improved Malted Grape Nuts", 1923 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "The Story of Milk"-Newspaper Clippings, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Value of Dairy Products in the Diet", 1931 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Visit with a Silent Milkman"- by Bosworth (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Publications, Notebook, John Norton Labs Milk Machinery Plans, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Publications-not by Bosworth, 1924-1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Course Notebook-Bacteriological Exercises, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Two Bound copies of Bosworth's publications, 1903-1918 (Box 3)
- Series V. Various other Files
  - Patent Information, 1920-1926 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Patent Information, 1922-1929 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Patent Information and Agreements, 1924-1929 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bank Statements, Salary Agreements, Investment Options, 1921-1924 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Experiments, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Similac Advertising, 1920-1939 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
  - Creamers-Manufacturer's Booklets (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photos-Creameries (Box 3, Folder 13)